<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>
<!--?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?-->
<!-- Transfer -->
<p:plan xmlns:p="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p:release projectid="m2e" version="1.5.0"/>
  <p:introduction>
    <p>M2E provides both a framework for building Maven-centric Eclipse
      tools and a set of tools and user interface elements directly
      consumable by Eclipse Users.</p>
    <div>
      <p>As a framework, M2E provides facilities to import and configure
        Maven projects in Eclipse workspace as well as APIs that allow
        m2e extensions to access Maven project metadata and participate in
        Maven project configuration and workspace build.</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      For the end user, M2E provides:
      <ul>
        <li>wizards to import existing and to create new Maven projects
        </li>
        <li>rich form-based and text-based pom.xml file editor</li>
        <li>launch configuration types to launch Maven build directly
          from Eclipse IDE
        </li>
        <li>access Maven repository index to browse repository contents
          and in various code-assist
        </li>
      </ul>
    </div>
    <p>Extensible JDT integration is provided by M2E as well.</p>
  </p:introduction>
  <p:release_deliverables>
    <ul>
      <li>feature to be installed into an Eclipse IDE installation using
        an update site.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p:release_deliverables>
  <p:release_milestones>
    <p:preamble>
      <p>
        Release milestones will be occurring at roughly 6 week
        intervals, and will be aligned with the
        <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Luna/Simultaneous_Release_Plan">
          Luna Simultaneous Release
        </a>
        train.
      </p>
    </p:preamble>
    <p:milestone date="25/06/2015" milestone="1.5.0">
      <div>1.5.0</div>
    </p:milestone>
  </p:release_milestones>
  

  <p:target_environments>
    <p>M2E requires minimum Java SE 6 VM.</p>
    <p>M2E is compatible with Eclipse 4.3 and Eclipse
      4.4 and is generally expected to work on each of these Eclipse
      releases respective referenced platforms.
    </p>
    <p:internationalization>
      <p>All m2e user interface elements are externalized, but only
        English strings are provided as the default resource
        bundles.
      </p>
    </p:internationalization>
  </p:target_environments>

  <p:compatibility_with_previous_releases>
    <h3>Compatibility with Eclipse m2e 1.4.x</h3>
    <p>
      <strong>API Contract Compatibility:</strong>
      m2e 1.5 API is backwards compatible with m2e 1.4.x.
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Workspace Compatibility:</strong>
      m2e 1.5 workspace metadata is backwards compatible with m2e 1.4.x
    </p>
  </p:compatibility_with_previous_releases>

  <p:themes_and_priorities>
    <p:preamble>
    </p:preamble>
    <p:theme name="Encourage comminity paritcipation">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <strong>Agile opensource project</strong>
            m2e is an agile opensource project and as such does not have 
            feature and/or bugfix roadmap. We encourage community members to come
            forward with ideas how to improve m2e and generally plan to prioritise 
            patches review over other m2e development activities. 
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
    </p:theme>
    <p:theme name="Stay current with Maven technologies">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <strong>Include latest released Maven version</strong>
            To maintain parity with bugfixes and new features available to 
            command line Maven users, m2e will include latest Maven version 
            available in time for Luna release. We will work with Maven core
            developers to align m2e and maven release schedules.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
    </p:theme>
  </p:themes_and_priorities>
</p:plan>
